Career Summary

Working as a java backend developer for five years. Developed multiple microservices of type Rest and SOAP, as well as specific implementations using frameworks such as Spring, Spring boot, JAXB2, JPA, Hibernate and others related to communication between services, security and payments. Also achieved both backend and frontend implementations in legacy software from the education industry, working on highly complex code bases, resolving bugs and implementing new features such as file systems and integrations with other institutions and providers. Results-oriented person, always willing to provide the best quality and performance in his developments.

Summary of Qualifications

Proficient In:

- Java 8, 11
- Javascript
- Typescript
- Postman
- Docker
- Spring boot
- Spring cloud
- React

- CSS Sass
- HTML
- XML -JSON
- Node
- Confluence
- Oracle DB
- PL/SQL
 - MySQL

Postgres

- Hibernate
- JPA
- Jakarta
- LombokOpenAPI
 - Git -Stash Markdown

- Scrum
- SOLID
- Concurrency
- Maven
- TDD

Languages

- Spanish (native)
- English (advanced)

Career History

Globant, Córdoba, Argentina

Full Stack Software Developer

Blackboard Anthology

- Design, development and documentation of new modules.
- Code maintenance and bug solving.
- Code reviewer.
- Knowledge sharing.
- Unit, integration and Rest test development.
- Performance analysis.

Tools/Technologies: Java, Spring, Postman, React, Postgres, Node, Typescript, Sass.

Kolektor UT, Córdoba, Argentina

Backend Java Developer

- Design, development and documentation of microservices.
- Design and development of custom business dependencies.
- Mentoring and support for less experienced developers.

Jun. 2022 – Aug. 2023

Jun. 2021 – Jan. 2022

• Unit and integration testing.

Tools/Technologies: Java, Spring, Postman, Jira, Confluence, Scrum, PL/SQL, Oracle DB.

UX Designer Virginia Gallardo, Córdoba, Argentina

Nov. 2018 – Feb. 2021

Backend Java Developer Freelance

- Design and development of web services.
- Technical design of paginated websites.

Tools/Technologies: Thymeleaf, Spring MVC, Java, HTML, MySQL.

Education

Siglo 21 University, Córdoba, Argentina

Feb. 2015 – Current

Degree in SA&D

BS, Software Engineering

UTN, Córdoba, Argentina BS, Electronic Engineering

Jan. 2008 – Feb 2009